<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./icons/arx.png" type="Manipulator" xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.10" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance" xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
    <name>Anonymization</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Node for anonymizing data using ARX Data Anonymization Tool.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>
        	Node for anonymizing sensitive personal data using <a href="https://arx.deidentifier.org">ARX Data Anonymization Tool</a>
        	<br></br>
        	<sub>
        		Developed by Alex Bondaletov
        	</sub>
        	<br></br>
        	<sup>
        		&lt;alex.bondaletov@yahoo.com&gt;
        	</sup>
        	
        </intro>
        
        <tab name="Columns">
        	<option name="Type">Attribute type. Possible options:
<pre>
0 | Identifying
1 | Quasi-identifying
2 | Sensitive
3 | Insensitive
</pre>
				(Either index or name could be used in flow variables)
        	</option>
        	<option name="File">Hierarchy file (*.ahs).</option>
        	<option name="Mode">Transformation mode. Possible options:
<pre>
0 | Generalization
1 | Microaggregation
2 | Clustering and microaggregation
</pre>        	
				(Either index or name could be used in flow variables)	
        	</option>
        	<option name="Weight">Attribute weight. Value in range [0.0, 1.0]. Default is 0.5.</option>
        	<option name="Minimum">Minimum generalization level.</option>
        	<option name="Maximum">Maximum generalization level.</option>
        	<option name="Function">Attribute processing function.  Possible options:
<pre>
0 | Arithmetic mean
1 | Geometric mean
2 | Median
3 | Interval
4 | Mode
</pre>        	
				(Either index or name could be used in flow variables)	
        	</option>
        	<option name="Ignore Missing Data">Should the function ignore missing data.</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Anonymization Config">
        	<option name="Number of threads">Number of partitions (threads). Input data will be split into # partitions to run in different threads simultaneously.</option>
        	<option name="Group by column">
        		Partition table by specified column. When unchecked - table will be partitioned into <b>Number of threads</b> parts of equal size.
        		For string columns - table will be partitioned by distinct values for this column, raising an error in case there are more
        		distinct values than specified number of threads.
        		For decimal and data/time columns - range of possible values will be split into <b>Number of threads</b> of equal length intervals.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Suppression limit">
        		Define the suppression limit, which is the maximal number of records that can be removed from the input dataset (in fraction). Value between 0.0 and 1.0.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Approximate: assume practical monotonicity">
        		The option "Approximate" can be enabled to compute an approximate solution with potentially significantly reduce execution times. 
        		The solution is guaranteed to fulfill the given privacy settings, but it might not be optimal regarding the data utility model specified.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Re-identification Risk Threshold">Thresholds for the highest risk of any record.
        		Used for measuring re-identification risks for three different attacker models: (1) the prosecutor scenario, (2) the journalist scenario and (3) the marketer scenario.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Add Class column to output table">
        		Option for including additional column representing equivalence class - a set of records which are indistinguishable regarding the specified quasi-identifying variables.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Omit rows with missing cells">
        		Exclude rows with 'missing cells' from the input table.
        		Throw an error if table contains missing cell when option is disabled.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Omit identifying columns">
        		Exclude 'identifying' columns from the result table.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Omit suppressed records">
        		Exclude suppressed records from the result table.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Heuristic Search Enabled">
        		Sets whether ARX will use a heuristic search strategy.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Limited number of steps">
        		The heuristic search algorithm will terminate after the given number of transformations have been checked.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Limited time [ms]">
        		The heuristic search algorithm will terminate after the given number of milliseconds.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Utility measure">
        		The model for quantifying data quality which will be used as an optimization function during the anonymization process.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Measure">Possible options:
<pre>
0 | Average equivalence class size
1 | Discernability
2 | Height
3 | Loss
4 | Non-uniform entropy
5 | Precision
6 | Ambiguity
7 | Normalized non-uniform entropy
8 | KL-Divergence
9 | Publisher payout (prosecutor)
10| Publisher payout (journalist)
11| Entropy-based information loss
12| Classification accuracy
</pre>        	
				(Either index or name could be used in flow variables)
        	</option>
        	<option name="Generalization/Suppression Factor">
        		Value between 0 (generalization) and 1 (suppression) specifying whether generalization or suppression should be preferred when transforming data.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Enable precomputation">
        		Precomputation is switched on when, for each quasi-identifier, 
        		the number of distinct data values divided by the total number of records in the dataset is lower than the configured <b>Precomputation threshold</b>.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Precomputation threshold">Value between 0.0 and 1.0.</option>
        	<option name="Aggregate Function">
        		Aggregate function will be used to compile the estimates obtained for the individual attributes of a dataset into a global value.
        		Possible options:
<pre>
0 | SUM
1 | MAX
2 | ARITHMETIC_MEAN
3 | GEOMETRIC_MEAN
4 | RANK
</pre>        	
				(Either index or name could be used in flow variables)
        	</option>
        	<option name="Population">
        		Population model is used by K-Map privacy model and for estimating re-identification risks.
        		Note: Privacy models based on population uniqueness assume that the dataset is a uniform sample of the population. If this is not the case, results may be inaccurate.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Region">
        		One of the regions with predefined population size.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Population size">
        		Population size could be entered manually.
        	</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Privacy Models">
        	<option name="Privacy Models">
        	 Configure privacy models. Refer <a href="https://arx.deidentifier.org/overview/privacy-criteria/">documentation</a> for details.
        	</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Research sample">
        	<option name="None">
        		Do not specify research sample. Research sample can be used by δ-presence and k-map privacy models.
        	</option>
        	<option name="All">
        		Use entire input table as sample subset.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Random selection">
        		Selecting records by random sampling.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Probability">
        		Random sampling probability. Value between 0.0 and 1.0.
        	</option>
        	<option name="Query selection">
        		Selecting records by querying the dataset
        	</option>
        	<option name="Query">
        		 The query syntax is as follows: fields and constants must be enclosed in single quotes.
        		 The following operators are supported: &gt;, &gt;=, &lt;, &lt;=, =, or, and, ( and ).
        		 Example: <pre>'age'&lt;'40' and 'gender'='M'</pre>
        	</option>
        	<option name="mode">
        		Flow variable holding sample selection mode. Possible values:
<pre>
0 | NONE
1 | ALL
2 | RANDOM
3 | QUERY
</pre>        		
        	</option>
        </tab>
    </fullDescription>
    
    <interactiveView name="Transformation View">
    	Select transformation from available options. There are two modes for visualization of anonymization models: list and graph. 
    	In graph mode use left click + drag in order to move the graph, and right-click + drag to zoom in and out. Both modes have filtering options, 
    	and it is possible to change anonymization model on fly.
    </interactiveView>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="Input table">Input table</inPort>
        <inPort index="1" name="Arx Hierarchy Configuration">Arx Hierarchy Configuration</inPort>
        <outPort index="0" name="Anonymized Data">Result table with anonymized data</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Stats">Statistics table</outPort>
        <outPort index="2" name="Suppressed records">Suppressed records</outPort>
        <outPort index="3" name="Attribute Risks">Attribute Risks</outPort>
        <outPort index="4" name="Stats Variables">Statistics in a form of flow variables. If partitioning is enabled only first row of statistic table is used</outPort>
    </ports>
    
</knimeNode>
